

# Elena Civati

### BIOTECHNOLOGIST

I am proficient in a wide range of scientific subjects and experienced in presenting and explaining scientific matters adapting them to the audience. I'm currently gaining IT skills needed to work in Health Data Science

## **Skills**

Time management and organisation Written and oral communication skills Autonomy Willingness to learn

#### IT Skills

R programming
Python programming
Unix
Galaxy platform
GitHub
HTML
Ms Office
LaTeX
Educational softwares (Geogebra, Cmap)

#### Languages

Italian - Native French - B2 English - B1

# **Areas of interest**

Natural cosmetics - Diy cosmetics Scientific communication - Debunking Intercultural meetings Passionate in Maths and Statistics

ADDRESS: 3, Avenue du Jura

01210 Ferney Voltaire (FR)

PHONE: +33-676037025

E-MAIL: elena.civati@gmail.com

NATIONALITY: Italian

DATE OF BIRTH: 08.11.1980

# **Career Summary**

**Science Teacher** Cias Formazione Professionale (Como, Italy) | Sep 2014 - Dec 2018 Biology, Chemistry, Cosmetology and Dermatology professor, working with both adolescent and adult students

**Supporting Teacher** Centro Vela Dislessia (Como, Italy) | Nov 2012 - Jun 2018 Helping high school and college students with Specific Learning Disabilities to improve their study method, focusing on Maths, Phisics and Chemistry

Online tutor

eCampus University (Italy) | Feb 2010 - Mar 2013

Guiding students along their university course, helping with choice and observance of their curriculum

Tutor

CESD S.r.l. (Italy) | Feb 2007 - Jul 2016

Teaching scientific subjects to students who couldn't attend school (workers, athletes...)
Tutoring for college students in the Chemistry and Pharmacology area

Morphometry technician

Procter & Gamble | Feb 2006 - Dec 2006

Performing computerized analysis of the spine as part of a prevention campaign against osteoporosis all around Italy

# Education

2005

Master's degree in Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, with a final mark of 110/110 University of Milan

1999

Scientific baccalaureate Liceo Galilei of Erba (Italy)

#### Certifications

"Data Science" Specialisation on Coursera, JHU (Jul 2021)

"Data Science: Foundations using R" Specialisation on Coursera, JHU (Mar 2021)

"Genomic Data Science" Specialisation on Coursera, Johns Hopkins University (Dec 2020)

DELF B2 - GRETA de l'Ain (Dec 2019)

French course B2 2/2 attendance certificate - Ifage Geneva (Nov 2019)

French course B2 1/2 attendance certificate - Ifage Geneva (Oct 2019)

BLSD rianimation and defribiliation - Comocuore Onlus (2018)

Pediatric rianimation - Italian Red Cross (2017)

Job security (according to italian law) (2015)

Metacognitive teaching - eCampus University (2011)